estes-express.com 2017-12-25

# Estes - Privacy Policy

## Effective Date: July 15, 2016

Estes Express Lines has created this privacy statement to help you understand your privacy rights and how we use information about our site visitors. This Policy describes the types of personal information we collect, use, and share about you. We also tell you how to update your information or contact us with questions about our privacy practices. This Policy applies only to this website (www.estes-express.com).

## Information We Collect and How We Use It

When you use certain features of our website, we may ask you to provide information that could identify you as an individual, such as when you provide information to create an account with My Estes or when you fill out a form such as an online Bill of Lading. Examples of personal information we may collect on our website includes:

  * Your contact information, such as name, email address, postal address of your business, telephone number, or fax number;
  * Your My Estes account user name and password;
  * Contact information for other people and businesses that you provide when you use certain features of our website (for instance, contact and delivery information for persons or companies who will receive shipments that you contract with us to deliver);
  * Information you enter regarding shipping services, such as information included in an online Bill of Lading (BOL) form or information you provide to enable us to offer brokerage services with another carrier;
  * Information you provide about a particular shipment, such as a PRO number, so that we may provide authorized users with tracking information or images of shipping documents;
  * Information you provide to us in user surveys that we send or arrange for a third party to send to you;
  * Location information if you access our site using a mobile device and opt in using your device or browser settings, as well as general location information based on your IP address, which we obtain through general site operations;
  * Information you provide to us and our service provider as part of a credit application so that we can investigate references and check your company’s credit history in order to determine whether, how much, and on what terms to extend credit to your company; and
  * Information you provide to us and our service providers in order to enable us to share information and invoices with you and allow you to provide information and make payments to us through Electronic Data Interchange (EDI).

## How We Use Your Information

We may use the information we obtain about you for a variety of purposes, including:

  * Providing information or services you requested, such as creating your My Estes account or providing information about a particular shipment or transaction; 
  * Communicating with you about our services and those of our affiliates and subsidiaries; 
  * Providing quotes to you for our services; 
  * Processing and fulfilling transactions, such as arranging to make shipments to you or on your behalf; 
  * Scheduling pickups of materials for shipping; 
  * Deciding whether to extend credit to your business; 
  * Providing tracking information for shipments or images of shipping documents to authorized persons who request this information; 
  * Handling claims arising from a shipment that you made or received; 
  * Allowing you to review billing information and open invoices; 
  * Gathering feedback about our products, services, and programs; 
  * Providing brokerage services for third parties to make shipments on your behalf; 
  * Providing customized content based on your use of our site, your preferences, and/or your location, depending on the type of information you have chosen to provide to us; 
  * Operating, evaluating, enhancing, and improving our business, products, services, communications, and similar activities; 
  * Analyzing, enhancing, and improving our online features, advertisements, marketing communications, and marketing strategies; 
  * Protecting against and preventing fraud, physical and financial loss, unauthorized transactions, claims, and other liabilities, and managing risk, including identifying unauthorized users or other security issues; 
  * Developing and customizing online advertisements for our services and those of our subsidiaries and affiliates to be served to you on our website, on websites of our affiliates or subsidiaries, and/or on websites of third parties who participate in certain advertising networks with us; 
  * Complying with applicable legal requirements, industry standards, and our policies, or enforcing compliance with those requirements; and 
  * In the case of our careers pages, evaluating job candidates and making hiring and other personnel decisions. 

We also may combine information we collect about you with other information we receive from additional sources. You may choose not to provide us with all of the information we request. In some cases, choosing not to provide information may prevent you from taking full advantage of our site’s features.

## Automated Collection and Use of Information

We, and certain third parties who provide services for us such as Google Analytics, receive or collect some information automatically when you visit our site or engage with other online content we provide using technology features such as:

_Cookies_. A cookie is a file saved to your computer or device that may be used to recognize our users when they return to our website, collect usage information, remember user’s preferences, and provide customized versions of our site. We use this information to evaluate our web traffic, improve our website and services, enhance our communications, and understand the effectiveness of our ad or promotional campaigns. For more information on your choices regarding cookies, see the Your Choices section below.

_Web Beacons_. Our site uses web beacons or pixels that monitor some types of use. These beacons may provide us with information such as the IP address of the computer or other device you used to access our site. We use this information to understand patterns of activity on our site, to improve its features, and to customize our presentation of content to our users, including online advertising.

_Online Advertising_. We provide online advertisements about our products and services on other parties’ websites. We may engage third party ad networks and analytics providers, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate how users interact with and respond to our ads. Estes may develop content and advertising based on the analytics and user information developed from cookies. For more information on your choices regarding cookies, see the Your Choices section below.

_Referrer Headers_. We may record referrer headers when you follow links to our website, which may be sent to us automatically by your web browser. In these cases, we may receive information such as the URL of the website that referred you to our site, or search queries you used to find our site. We use this information to understand our web traffic, to improve our services, to increase their accessibility to search engines and others, and to monitor our advertising campaigns.The types of information that are automatically collected through these tools may include:

  * Pages you view, links you click or hover over, and selections you make on our website.
  * Your browser's HTTP referrer header.
  * Features you use, preferences you set, and selections you make.
  * Your web browser type and version.
  * The operating system type and version of the device you are using to access the service.
  * The Internet protocol (IP) address of the device you are using to access our website.

## How We Share Your Information

We may share information with trusted parties, such as:

  * With our subsidiaries and affiliates;
  * With third party service providers to help us host and operate the website; gather, save, analyze and use information you enter into online forms; accept payments for services you order through the website; analyze data regarding usage of the website; send mail or email to you for marketing or promotional purposes; conduct surveys; or arrange for exchange of information and payments for shipping and other business purposes between you and Estes through Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) services;
  * With a third party service provider when you use our website to submit a credit application to us. The third party uses that information and other information available to it to provide us an analysis that we use to make credit determinations.
  * With other carriers when you enter an online request for us to provide brokerage services or time-critical services to help you place your shipment with another carrier in the event our services are not suited to meet your needs in a particular situation;
  * With advertising networks to serve interest-based advertisements to you on our website and on websites of our affiliates and subsidiaries and certain third parties who participate in advertising networks with us. If you prefer not to receive advertisements through advertising networks, you may follow the instructions included in such advertisements to opt out of receiving them.
  * When reasonably requested or required by law enforcement authorities or other government officials;
  * When required by law or in response to legal process;
  * When we believe disclosure is appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss;
  * When reasonably necessary to an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; and
  * Although unlikely, in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets.

## Online Advertising and Tracking

You may receive interest-based advertisements from us and from our ad providers that are specifically tailored to your interests. These ads have been selected based on your use of our website and services, information you provide to us, and/or other information obtained by us and our ad providers. It is also possible that such interest-based advertising has been tailored to the interests that advertisers have inferred from your browsing of our websites, or from your use of other websites or applications with which a third-party has partnered, in order to provide advertising.

We also may engage with third-party advertising networks. We share aggregate, but not personally identifiable information with these third parties, but ad networks may set and access their own cookies, beacons and similar technologies on your device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, including usage information, by tracking your online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third parties. These ad networks may use the information they collect for their own purposes. We and our network advertisers may target advertisements for our products and services and those of our affiliates and subsidiaries on our website and on other websites you may visit.

## Your Choices

We offer you certain choices about the information we collect, how we use and share information, and how we communicate with you. To help protect your privacy, when you exercise these choices we may take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as requiring a password.

By contacting us as shown in the Contact Us section of this Policy, you may opt out of receiving communications from us, such as emails and surveys. You also have the following specific opt-out choices:

  * Marketing communications. You may opt out of specific communications (such as marketing emails) by following the opt-out instructions contained in the communication. 
  * Cookies. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. However, rejecting cookies may affect your user experience, and you may not be able to access or use certain features of our sites. In addition, disabling cookies may invalidate opt outs that rely on cookies, such as targeted advertising opt outs. 
  * Targeted advertising. If you prefer to not receive targeted advertising, you can opt out of some network advertising programs that use your information. These network advertising programs may allow you to view and manage the interest categories they have compiled from your online browsing activities. These interest categories help determine the types of targeted advertisements you may receive. To find out more, look for icons or other information displayed in the ads.
  * Geographic location. When you use our website on your mobile device, you may choose not to share your location with us by adjusting the device’s location services settings. For instructions on changing the relevant settings, please contact your plan provider or device manufacturer.

While we will take all reasonable steps to honor your choices with respect to your personal information, you should be aware that it is not always possible to delete all of your information for technical reasons. For example, we may store personal information in long-term archives or backups or retain an identifier to honor your opt out choices. We will continue to send you service-related communications, and we may need to keep the information we have collected about you for record keeping, analysis, or other reasons, to the extent permitted by law.

## California Residents

If you are a California resident, you may contact us to request information about circumstances in which we share certain personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes. To request information, please contact us as indicated in the Contact Us section of this Policy. Our website recognizes do-not-track signals sent by your browser. Certain services that we offer through our website may not work correctly if your browser sends a do-not-track signal, and it may be necessary for you to adjust your settings in order to use those services.

## Information Security

The nature of our business requires us to collect and maintain certain personal information, and we understand that we have a responsibility to protect it. To do so, we maintain appropriate administrative, physical, and technical safeguards that are designed to safeguard your personal information from accidental, unlawful, or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure, or use. Your My Estes account is protected by your log-in credentials, which you must keep secure and confidential.

We also offer you the option of interacting with the My Estes portion of our website and sharing and viewing information on a secure or unsecure platform. When you opt to sign in to My Estes using the secure platform, the information you view and share is encrypted using SSL encryption. Encryption is the process of disguising information as data unintelligible to an unauthorized person. On the other hand, decryption or decipherment is the process of converting this ciphertext back into its original format. When used between you and Estes Express Lines, this technology encrypts your personal information as you send it to us so that only Estes Express Lines can decrypt it. When we send personal or account information to you, this technology encrypts it and only you have the capability to decrypt. We use the Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) communications protocol when you log in to the My Estes portion of our website by opting to sign in “secure” mode. Please be advised that if you do not elect to sign in using the “secure” mode, your communications with and use of the My Estes portion of our website will not be secured with SSL encryption.

Many of the services we provide on this website use access codes or passwords, which provide an additional layer of security for your information. We communicate our privacy and security guidelines and standards to Estes employees who access personal information for purposes described in this policy, and we enforce these requirements within the company.

## Accessing and Correcting Your Information

Estes endeavors to maintain accurate information and provide you with options to update your information. You can log into your account and modify your information using your log-in credentials. You also may request that we update your information by contacting us as described in the Contact Us section of this Policy.

## International Data Transfer

Please be advised that information described in this policy will be maintained and processed in the United States. Other countries, including the United States, may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you reside. No matter where we process personal information, that information will be subject to the policies and protections described by this Policy.

## Links to Other Sites

We may provide links to other websites for your convenience and information. Since these sites are not owned, controlled, or operated by Estes, we cannot control how information collected by these linked sites will be used, shared, or secured. If you visit linked sites, we strongly suggest that you review the privacy notices or policies posted at those sites. We are not responsible for the content of linked sites, your use of them, or the information practices of their operators.

## Contact Us

You may ask a question, request that we update your information, or submit a complaint by contacting us at:

  * Email [TeamSocial@estes-express.com](mailto:TeamSocial@estes-express.com)
  * Postal Mail to the following address:

Webmaster  
Estes Express Lines  
P.O. Box 25612  
Richmond, VA 23260-5612 

## Updates to Our Privacy Policy

As we modify our information collection or privacy practices, and as privacy laws evolve, it may be necessary to revise or update this Policy. We will always change the effective date on the Policy to reflect when it was last revised. We will continue to protect your personal information in accordance with applicable law and as described by our current Privacy Policy.
